[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "HTML stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Hyper Text Markup Language",
            "High Text Machine Language",
            "Hyperlinks Text Mark Language",
            "Home Tool Markup Language"
        ],
        "answer": "Hyper Text Markup Language"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Which tag is used to create a hyperlink?",
        "options": [
            "<link>",
            "<a>",
            "<href>",
            "<url>"
        ],
        "answer": "<a>"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Which CSS property controls text size?",
        "options": [
            "font-style",
            "text-size",
            "font-size",
            "size"
        ],
        "answer": "font-size"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Which is NOT a JavaScript data type?",
        "options": [
            "String",
            "Boolean",
            "Undefined",
            "Character"
        ],
        "answer": "Character"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Which symbol is used for comments in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "<!-- -->",
            "//",
            "#",
            "**"
        ],
        "answer": "//"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Which method converts JSON to object?",
        "options": [
            "JSON.parse()",
            "JSON.stringify()",
            "JSON.convert()",
            "JSON.object()"
        ],
        "answer": "JSON.parse()"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Which library is used for DOM manipulation?",
        "options": [
            "React",
            "Vue",
            "jQuery",
            "Node"
        ],
        "answer": "jQuery"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Bootstrap is a ____ framework?",
        "options": [
            "Backend",
            "Frontend",
            "Database",
            "Testing"
        ],
        "answer": "Frontend"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Which Bootstrap class creates a button?",
        "options": [
            "btn",
            "button",
            "btn-primary",
            "btn-all"
        ],
        "answer": "btn"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Tailwind CSS is based on?",
        "options": [
            "Components",
            "Utility classes",
            "Inline CSS",
            "Themes"
        ],
        "answer": "Utility classes"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "React is mainly used for?",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Server",
            "Building UI",
            "Authentication"
        ],
        "answer": "Building UI"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "Which hook manages state in React?",
        "options": [
            "useEffect",
            "useState",
            "useContext",
            "useRef"
        ],
        "answer": "useState"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Which hook runs side effects?",
        "options": [
            "useState",
            "useMemo",
            "useEffect",
            "useRef"
        ],
        "answer": "useEffect"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "JSX stands for?",
        "options": [
            "JavaScript XML",
            "JSON XML",
            "Java Syntax X",
            "JavaScript Extension"
        ],
        "answer": "JavaScript XML"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "Props in React are?",
        "options": [
            "Mutable",
            "Read-only",
            "Global",
            "State"
        ],
        "answer": "Read-only"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Node.js is?",
        "options": [
            "Frontend framework",
            "Runtime environment",
            "Database",
            "Browser"
        ],
        "answer": "Runtime environment"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Express is used for?",
        "options": [
            "UI",
            "Routing",
            "Database",
            "CSS"
        ],
        "answer": "Routing"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "Which command initializes Node project?",
        "options": [
            "npm start",
            "npm init",
            "node init",
            "npm install"
        ],
        "answer": "npm init"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "Which method handles GET requests in Express?",
        "options": [
            "app.post()",
            "app.get()",
            "app.put()",
            "app.delete()"
        ],
        "answer": "app.get()"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "Middleware in Express is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Styling",
            "Request handling",
            "Database",
            "UI"
        ],
        "answer": "Request handling"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "Laravel is written in?",
        "options": [
            "Java",
            "Python",
            "PHP",
            "JS"
        ],
        "answer": "PHP"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "Which file defines routes in Laravel?",
        "options": [
            "web.php",
            "route.php",
            "index.php",
            "api.js"
        ],
        "answer": "web.php"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "Laravel ORM is?",
        "options": [
            "Doctrine",
            "Hibernate",
            "Eloquent",
            "Active"
        ],
        "answer": "Eloquent"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "Blade is Laravelâ€™s?",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Template engine",
            "Auth",
            "Cache"
        ],
        "answer": "Template engine"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "Which artisan command runs server?",
        "options": [
            "php artisan serve",
            "php artisan start",
            "php run",
            "laravel serve"
        ],
        "answer": "php artisan serve"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "MySQL is a?",
        "options": [
            "NoSQL DB",
            "Relational DB",
            "Frontend tool",
            "API"
        ],
        "answer": "Relational DB"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "MongoDB stores data as?",
        "options": [
            "Tables",
            "Rows",
            "Documents",
            "Columns"
        ],
        "answer": "Documents"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "Which query fetches all rows?",
        "options": [
            "SELECT *",
            "GET ALL",
            "FETCH",
            "READ"
        ],
        "answer": "SELECT *"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "Primary key is?",
        "options": [
            "Duplicate",
            "Nullable",
            "Unique",
            "Optional"
        ],
        "answer": "Unique"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "Foreign key is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Indexing",
            "Relations",
            "Speed",
            "Backup"
        ],
        "answer": "Relations"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "JWT stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Java Web Token",
            "JSON Web Token",
            "JS Web Token",
            "JavaScript Web Token"
        ],
        "answer": "JSON Web Token"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "question": "JWT contains?",
        "options": [
            "Header, Payload, Signature",
            "Body only",
            "Token ID",
            "Session ID"
        ],
        "answer": "Header, Payload, Signature"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "question": "Sanctum is used for?",
        "options": [
            "UI",
            "Authentication",
            "Queue",
            "Cache"
        ],
        "answer": "Authentication"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "question": "Passport is used in?",
        "options": [
            "Laravel",
            "Node.js",
            "React",
            "MySQL"
        ],
        "answer": "Node.js"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "question": "Bearer token is sent in?",
        "options": [
            "Body",
            "Query",
            "Header",
            "Cookie"
        ],
        "answer": "Header"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "question": "REST API uses which protocol?",
        "options": [
            "FTP",
            "SMTP",
            "HTTP",
            "SSH"
        ],
        "answer": "HTTP"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "question": "Which HTTP method creates data?",
        "options": [
            "GET",
            "POST",
            "PUT",
            "DELETE"
        ],
        "answer": "POST"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "question": "Which HTTP method updates data?",
        "options": [
            "GET",
            "POST",
            "PUT",
            "PATCH"
        ],
        "answer": "PUT"
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "question": "Which HTTP method deletes data?",
        "options": [
            "REMOVE",
            "DELETE",
            "DROP",
            "CLEAR"
        ],
        "answer": "DELETE"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "question": "Status code 200 means?",
        "options": [
            "Error",
            "Success",
            "Unauthorized",
            "Not Found"
        ],
        "answer": "Success"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "question": "Git is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Styling",
            "Version control",
            "Database",
            "Hosting"
        ],
        "answer": "Version control"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "question": "Which command checks git status?",
        "options": [
            "git check",
            "git status",
            "git log",
            "git branch"
        ],
        "answer": "git status"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "question": "GitHub is?",
        "options": [
            "IDE",
            "Hosting platform",
            "Database",
            "Framework"
        ],
        "answer": "Hosting platform"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "question": "Which command pushes code?",
        "options": [
            "git add",
            "git commit",
            "git push",
            "git pull"
        ],
        "answer": "git push"
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "question": "Postman is used for?",
        "options": [
            "UI",
            "API testing",
            "Database",
            "Hosting"
        ],
        "answer": "API testing"
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "question": "Which git command creates a new branch?",
        "options": [
            "git branch",
            "git checkout",
            "git new",
            "git create"
        ],
        "answer": "git branch"
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "question": "Which git command switches branch?",
        "options": [
            "git move",
            "git switch",
            "git change",
            "git swap"
        ],
        "answer": "git switch"
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "question": "Which HTTP status means Unauthorized?",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "401",
            "404",
            "500"
        ],
        "answer": "401"
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "question": "Which HTTP status means Not Found?",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "403",
            "404",
            "500"
        ],
        "answer": "404"
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "question": "Which HTTP status means Server Error?",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "401",
            "404",
            "500"
        ],
        "answer": "500"
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "question": "Which JavaScript keyword declares constant?",
        "options": [
            "var",
            "let",
            "const",
            "static"
        ],
        "answer": "const"
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "question": "Which keyword creates block scoped variable?",
        "options": [
            "var",
            "let",
            "global",
            "scope"
        ],
        "answer": "let"
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "question": "Which array method adds element at end?",
        "options": [
            "push()",
            "pop()",
            "shift()",
            "unshift()"
        ],
        "answer": "push()"
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "question": "Which array method removes last element?",
        "options": [
            "pop()",
            "push()",
            "shift()",
            "slice()"
        ],
        "answer": "pop()"
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "question": "Which function converts object to JSON?",
        "options": [
            "JSON.parse()",
            "JSON.stringify()",
            "JSON.convert()",
            "JSON.object()"
        ],
        "answer": "JSON.stringify()"
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "question": "What is closure in JavaScript?",
        "options": [
            "Function inside function",
            "Loop",
            "Condition",
            "Array"
        ],
        "answer": "Function inside function"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "question": "Promise states include?",
        "options": [
            "Pending, Resolved, Rejected",
            "Start, End",
            "True, False",
            "Init, Done"
        ],
        "answer": "Pending, Resolved, Rejected"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "question": "Which keyword handles errors?",
        "options": [
            "catch",
            "try",
            "throw",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "question": "Which method executes async code?",
        "options": [
            "await",
            "sync",
            "delay",
            "wait"
        ],
        "answer": "await"
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "question": "Which loop iterates array easily?",
        "options": [
            "for",
            "forEach",
            "while",
            "do-while"
        ],
        "answer": "forEach"
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "question": "Which React hook accesses context?",
        "options": [
            "useState",
            "useEffect",
            "useContext",
            "useReducer"
        ],
        "answer": "useContext"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "question": "Which hook improves performance?",
        "options": [
            "useEffect",
            "useMemo",
            "useState",
            "useRef"
        ],
        "answer": "useMemo"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "question": "Which hook stores mutable value?",
        "options": [
            "useRef",
            "useState",
            "useEffect",
            "useMemo"
        ],
        "answer": "useRef"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "question": "React renders UI using?",
        "options": [
            "Real DOM",
            "Virtual DOM",
            "Shadow DOM",
            "HTML DOM"
        ],
        "answer": "Virtual DOM"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "question": "Key prop is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Styling",
            "Identification",
            "State",
            "Events"
        ],
        "answer": "Identification"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "question": "Which Node module handles files?",
        "options": [
            "http",
            "fs",
            "path",
            "url"
        ],
        "answer": "fs"
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "question": "Which Node module creates server?",
        "options": [
            "fs",
            "http",
            "express",
            "server"
        ],
        "answer": "http"
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "question": "Which Express method parses JSON?",
        "options": [
            "express.json()",
            "bodyParser()",
            "app.json()",
            "json.parse()"
        ],
        "answer": "express.json()"
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "question": "Which status code is Created?",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "201",
            "204",
            "301"
        ],
        "answer": "201"
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "question": "Which tool handles environment variables?",
        "options": [
            "dotenv",
            "env",
            "config",
            "settings"
        ],
        "answer": "dotenv"
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "question": "Which Laravel file stores middleware?",
        "options": [
            "Kernel.php",
            "Handler.php",
            "Controller.php",
            "Route.php"
        ],
        "answer": "Kernel.php"
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "question": "Which command creates middleware?",
        "options": [
            "make:middleware",
            "create:middleware",
            "artisan middleware",
            "new middleware"
        ],
        "answer": "make:middleware"
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "question": "Which Laravel feature handles queues?",
        "options": [
            "Jobs",
            "Events",
            "Cache",
            "Tasks"
        ],
        "answer": "Jobs"
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "question": "Which command clears route cache?",
        "options": [
            "route:clear",
            "cache:clear",
            "config:clear",
            "view:clear"
        ],
        "answer": "route:clear"
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "question": "Which blade directive checks condition?",
        "options": [
            "@foreach",
            "@if",
            "@while",
            "@switch"
        ],
        "answer": "@if"
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "question": "Which MongoDB method inserts data?",
        "options": [
            "insertOne()",
            "add()",
            "save()",
            "push()"
        ],
        "answer": "insertOne()"
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "question": "Which MongoDB method finds data?",
        "options": [
            "find()",
            "get()",
            "select()",
            "fetch()"
        ],
        "answer": "find()"
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "question": "Which SQL command deletes record?",
        "options": [
            "REMOVE",
            "DROP",
            "DELETE",
            "CLEAR"
        ],
        "answer": "DELETE"
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "question": "Which SQL clause filters records?",
        "options": [
            "WHERE",
            "FROM",
            "SELECT",
            "ORDER"
        ],
        "answer": "WHERE"
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "question": "Index in DB improves?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Speed",
            "Size",
            "Backup"
        ],
        "answer": "Speed"
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "question": "JWT is stateless because?",
        "options": [
            "Stored in DB",
            "Stored on server",
            "Stored on client",
            "Uses cookies"
        ],
        "answer": "Stored on client"
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "question": "JWT expiry is set using?",
        "options": [
            "exp",
            "time",
            "ttl",
            "end"
        ],
        "answer": "exp"
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "question": "Sanctum supports?",
        "options": [
            "SPA Auth",
            "Session Auth",
            "Token Auth",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "question": "Passport strategy example?",
        "options": [
            "JWT",
            "Local",
            "OAuth",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "question": "Auth middleware checks?",
        "options": [
            "Request",
            "Token",
            "User",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "question": "REST API should be?",
        "options": [
            "Stateful",
            "Stateless",
            "Session based",
            "Cookie based"
        ],
        "answer": "Stateless"
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "question": "Which format is commonly used in APIs?",
        "options": [
            "XML",
            "JSON",
            "TXT",
            "CSV"
        ],
        "answer": "JSON"
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "question": "Which header sends auth token?",
        "options": [
            "Content-Type",
            "Authorization",
            "Accept",
            "Host"
        ],
        "answer": "Authorization"
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "question": "CORS relates to?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Database",
            "Styling",
            "Routing"
        ],
        "answer": "Security"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "question": "API rate limiting prevents?",
        "options": [
            "Spam",
            "Auth",
            "Cache",
            "Errors"
        ],
        "answer": "Spam"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "question": "Which git command merges branch?",
        "options": [
            "git join",
            "git merge",
            "git pull",
            "git push"
        ],
        "answer": "git merge"
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "question": "Which git command downloads changes?",
        "options": [
            "git fetch",
            "git pull",
            "git clone",
            "git load"
        ],
        "answer": "git pull"
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "question": "Postman environment is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Variables",
            "Themes",
            "Users",
            "Routes"
        ],
        "answer": "Variables"
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "question": "Which tool debugs API?",
        "options": [
            "Git",
            "Postman",
            "Docker",
            "NPM"
        ],
        "answer": "Postman"
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "question": "Which HTTP method is idempotent?",
        "options": [
            "GET",
            "PUT",
            "DELETE",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "question": "MVC stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Model View Controller",
            "Main View Code",
            "Module View Control",
            "Model Version Controller"
        ],
        "answer": "Model View Controller"
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "question": "Controller handles?",
        "options": [
            "Logic",
            "UI",
            "DB",
            "CSS"
        ],
        "answer": "Logic"
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "question": "Model interacts with?",
        "options": [
            "Routes",
            "Views",
            "Database",
            "CSS"
        ],
        "answer": "Database"
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "question": "View handles?",
        "options": [
            "Logic",
            "Routing",
            "UI",
            "Auth"
        ],
        "answer": "UI"
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "question": "Full stack developer works on?",
        "options": [
            "Frontend",
            "Backend",
            "Database",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "question": "Which CSS property controls element spacing inside?",
        "options": [
            "margin",
            "padding",
            "gap",
            "space"
        ],
        "answer": "padding"
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "question": "Which CSS property controls spacing outside element?",
        "options": [
            "margin",
            "padding",
            "border",
            "gap"
        ],
        "answer": "margin"
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "question": "Flexbox main axis is controlled by?",
        "options": [
            "align-items",
            "justify-content",
            "flex-wrap",
            "align-content"
        ],
        "answer": "justify-content"
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "question": "Which Tailwind class applies flexbox?",
        "options": [
            "flex",
            "d-flex",
            "display-flex",
            "box-flex"
        ],
        "answer": "flex"
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "question": "Bootstrap grid is based on how many columns?",
        "options": [
            "10",
            "11",
            "12",
            "16"
        ],
        "answer": "12"
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "question": "Which JavaScript method selects element by ID?",
        "options": [
            "querySelector()",
            "getElement()",
            "getElementById()",
            "selectById()"
        ],
        "answer": "getElementById()"
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "question": "Which operator checks value and type?",
        "options": [
            "==",
            "=",
            "===",
            "!="
        ],
        "answer": "==="
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "question": "NaN stands for?",
        "options": [
            "No any Number",
            "Not a Name",
            "Not a Number",
            "Null and Number"
        ],
        "answer": "Not a Number"
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "question": "Which keyword stops loop?",
        "options": [
            "stop",
            "end",
            "break",
            "exit"
        ],
        "answer": "break"
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "question": "Which keyword skips iteration?",
        "options": [
            "skip",
            "continue",
            "next",
            "pass"
        ],
        "answer": "continue"
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "question": "Which React hook handles complex state?",
        "options": [
            "useState",
            "useEffect",
            "useReducer",
            "useMemo"
        ],
        "answer": "useReducer"
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "question": "Controlled component means?",
        "options": [
            "DOM controls state",
            "React controls state",
            "Browser controls state",
            "Redux controls state"
        ],
        "answer": "React controls state"
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "question": "React Fragment is used to?",
        "options": [
            "Add div",
            "Group elements",
            "Improve CSS",
            "Handle state"
        ],
        "answer": "Group elements"
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "question": "Which prop handles input change?",
        "options": [
            "onClick",
            "onSubmit",
            "onChange",
            "onInput"
        ],
        "answer": "onChange"
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "question": "SPA stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Single Page App",
            "Server Page App",
            "Simple Page App",
            "Static Page App"
        ],
        "answer": "Single Page App"
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "question": "Which Express middleware handles errors?",
        "options": [
            "next()",
            "error()",
            "catch()",
            "throw()"
        ],
        "answer": "next()"
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "question": "Which Node package manages dependencies?",
        "options": [
            "node",
            "npm",
            "express",
            "yarn"
        ],
        "answer": "npm"
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "question": "Which file lists Node dependencies?",
        "options": [
            "package.json",
            "node.json",
            "config.json",
            "dependencies.json"
        ],
        "answer": "package.json"
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "question": "Which Express method sends response?",
        "options": [
            "res.send()",
            "res.get()",
            "res.read()",
            "res.output()"
        ],
        "answer": "res.send()"
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "question": "Which status code means No Content?",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "201",
            "204",
            "301"
        ],
        "answer": "204"
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "question": "Which Laravel command creates controller?",
        "options": [
            "make:controller",
            "create:controller",
            "artisan controller",
            "new:controller"
        ],
        "answer": "make:controller"
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "question": "Which Laravel method validates request?",
        "options": [
            "check()",
            "validate()",
            "verify()",
            "rules()"
        ],
        "answer": "validate()"
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "question": "Which Laravel helper redirects user?",
        "options": [
            "view()",
            "route()",
            "redirect()",
            "url()"
        ],
        "answer": "redirect()"
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "question": "Which Laravel feature schedules tasks?",
        "options": [
            "Queue",
            "Cron",
            "Scheduler",
            "Job"
        ],
        "answer": "Scheduler"
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "question": "Which Laravel command lists routes?",
        "options": [
            "route:list",
            "routes:show",
            "list:route",
            "show:routes"
        ],
        "answer": "route:list"
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "question": "Which SQL command updates record?",
        "options": [
            "UPDATE",
            "MODIFY",
            "CHANGE",
            "SET"
        ],
        "answer": "UPDATE"
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "question": "Which SQL clause sorts result?",
        "options": [
            "GROUP BY",
            "ORDER BY",
            "SORT",
            "FILTER"
        ],
        "answer": "ORDER BY"
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "question": "MongoDB is?",
        "options": [
            "Relational DB",
            "NoSQL DB",
            "Graph DB",
            "File DB"
        ],
        "answer": "NoSQL DB"
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "question": "Which MongoDB field is unique by default?",
        "options": [
            "id",
            "_id",
            "uuid",
            "key"
        ],
        "answer": "_id"
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "question": "Normalization reduces?",
        "options": [
            "Performance",
            "Redundancy",
            "Security",
            "Indexes"
        ],
        "answer": "Redundancy"
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "question": "JWT is usually stored in?",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Session",
            "LocalStorage",
            "Cache"
        ],
        "answer": "LocalStorage"
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "question": "Which auth uses cookies by default?",
        "options": [
            "JWT",
            "Sanctum",
            "Passport",
            "OAuth"
        ],
        "answer": "Sanctum"
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "question": "OAuth is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Authorization",
            "Authentication",
            "Styling",
            "Database"
        ],
        "answer": "Authorization"
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "question": "Token-based auth is?",
        "options": [
            "Stateful",
            "Stateless",
            "Session based",
            "Cookie based"
        ],
        "answer": "Stateless"
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "question": "Refresh token is used to?",
        "options": [
            "Login",
            "Extend access",
            "Logout",
            "Encrypt"
        ],
        "answer": "Extend access"
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "question": "REST API uses resources identified by?",
        "options": [
            "ID",
            "URL",
            "Token",
            "Session"
        ],
        "answer": "URL"
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "question": "Which HTTP method partially updates?",
        "options": [
            "PUT",
            "PATCH",
            "POST",
            "GET"
        ],
        "answer": "PATCH"
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "question": "Which response format is lightweight?",
        "options": [
            "XML",
            "JSON",
            "HTML",
            "CSV"
        ],
        "answer": "JSON"
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "question": "API pagination improves?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Performance",
            "Auth",
            "UI"
        ],
        "answer": "Performance"
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "question": "Idempotent request means?",
        "options": [
            "Same result always",
            "Faster request",
            "Cached request",
            "Secure request"
        ],
        "answer": "Same result always"
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "question": "Which git command shows commit history?",
        "options": [
            "git log",
            "git status",
            "git show",
            "git history"
        ],
        "answer": "git log"
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "question": "Fork in GitHub means?",
        "options": [
            "Clone repo",
            "Copy repo",
            "Delete repo",
            "Merge repo"
        ],
        "answer": "Copy repo"
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "question": "Pull Request is used to?",
        "options": [
            "Push code",
            "Review code",
            "Delete branch",
            "Deploy app"
        ],
        "answer": "Review code"
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "question": "Which tool tests APIs manually?",
        "options": [
            "Git",
            "Postman",
            "Webpack",
            "Nginx"
        ],
        "answer": "Postman"
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "question": "Which HTTP status means Forbidden?",
        "options": [
            "401",
            "403",
            "404",
            "500"
        ],
        "answer": "403"
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "question": "MVC improves code?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Maintainability",
            "Speed",
            "Size"
        ],
        "answer": "Maintainability"
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "question": "Separation of concerns means?",
        "options": [
            "One file",
            "One responsibility",
            "More logic",
            "Less files"
        ],
        "answer": "One responsibility"
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "question": "Full stack developer should understand?",
        "options": [
            "Frontend",
            "Backend",
            "Database",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "question": "Clean code is?",
        "options": [
            "Readable",
            "Short",
            "Fast",
            "Complex"
        ],
        "answer": "Readable"
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "question": "Best practice for production secrets?",
        "options": [
            "Hardcode",
            "Commit to git",
            "Use env variables",
            "Store in JS"
        ],
        "answer": "Use env variables"
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "question": "Which CSS property controls layout using flexbox?",
        "options": [
            "display",
            "position",
            "float",
            "overflow"
        ],
        "answer": "display"
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "question": "Which flexbox value enables flex layout?",
        "options": [
            "block",
            "inline",
            "flex",
            "grid"
        ],
        "answer": "flex"
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "question": "Which Tailwind class adds padding?",
        "options": [
            "m-4",
            "p-4",
            "px-4",
            "py-4"
        ],
        "answer": "p-4"
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "question": "Which Bootstrap class centers text?",
        "options": [
            "text-center",
            "align-center",
            "center-text",
            "justify-center"
        ],
        "answer": "text-center"
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "question": "Which HTML element is semantic?",
        "options": [
            "<div>",
            "<span>",
            "<section>",
            "<b>"
        ],
        "answer": "<section>"
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "question": "Which operator compares value and type?",
        "options": [
            "==",
            "=",
            "===",
            "!="
        ],
        "answer": "==="
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "question": "Which keyword stops loop execution?",
        "options": [
            "continue",
            "stop",
            "exit",
            "break"
        ],
        "answer": "break"
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "question": "Which function delays execution?",
        "options": [
            "setTimeout()",
            "setInterval()",
            "delay()",
            "wait()"
        ],
        "answer": "setTimeout()"
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "question": "Which array method returns new array?",
        "options": [
            "forEach()",
            "map()",
            "push()",
            "pop()"
        ],
        "answer": "map()"
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "question": "Which prop renders children components?",
        "options": [
            "props.data",
            "props.render",
            "props.children",
            "props.child"
        ],
        "answer": "props.children"
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "question": "React component must return?",
        "options": [
            "HTML",
            "JSX",
            "String",
            "Object"
        ],
        "answer": "JSX"
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "question": "Which lifecycle hook runs once?",
        "options": [
            "useEffect([])",
            "useState()",
            "useMemo()",
            "useRef()"
        ],
        "answer": "useEffect([])"
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "question": "Which router is used in React?",
        "options": [
            "react-router-dom",
            "react-router",
            "react-navigation",
            "router-js"
        ],
        "answer": "react-router-dom"
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "question": "Which method sends JSON response?",
        "options": [
            "res.send()",
            "res.json()",
            "res.end()",
            "res.write()"
        ],
        "answer": "res.json()"
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "question": "Which Node feature supports non-blocking IO?",
        "options": [
            "Threads",
            "Event loop",
            "Promises",
            "Callbacks"
        ],
        "answer": "Event loop"
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "question": "Which HTTP header defines response type?",
        "options": [
            "Accept",
            "Content-Type",
            "Authorization",
            "Origin"
        ],
        "answer": "Content-Type"
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "question": "Which npm command installs dependency?",
        "options": [
            "npm start",
            "npm add",
            "npm install",
            "npm init"
        ],
        "answer": "npm install"
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "question": "Which artisan command lists routes?",
        "options": [
            "route:list",
            "routes:show",
            "list:route",
            "show:routes"
        ],
        "answer": "route:list"
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "question": "Which relationship defines one-to-one?",
        "options": [
            "hasMany",
            "belongsToMany",
            "hasOne",
            "manyToOne"
        ],
        "answer": "hasOne"
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "question": "Which Laravel feature handles scheduling?",
        "options": [
            "Queues",
            "Cron",
            "Scheduler",
            "Tasks"
        ],
        "answer": "Scheduler"
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "question": "Which SQL function counts records?",
        "options": [
            "SUM()",
            "TOTAL()",
            "COUNT()",
            "NUMBER()"
        ],
        "answer": "COUNT()"
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "question": "Which database normal form removes redundancy?",
        "options": [
            "1NF",
            "2NF",
            "3NF",
            "BCNF"
        ],
        "answer": "3NF"
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "question": "Which query sorts results?",
        "options": [
            "GROUP BY",
            "ORDER BY",
            "SORT",
            "FILTER"
        ],
        "answer": "ORDER BY"
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "question": "Which SQL join returns matching rows?",
        "options": [
            "LEFT JOIN",
            "RIGHT JOIN",
            "INNER JOIN",
            "FULL JOIN"
        ],
        "answer": "INNER JOIN"
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "question": "JWT signature ensures?",
        "options": [
            "Speed",
            "Encryption",
            "Integrity",
            "Compression"
        ],
        "answer": "Integrity"
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "question": "Token based auth is?",
        "options": [
            "Stateful",
            "Stateless",
            "Cookie based",
            "Session based"
        ],
        "answer": "Stateless"
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "question": "Which header prevents CORS error?",
        "options": [
            "Access-Control-Allow-Origin",
            "Authorization",
            "Accept",
            "Origin"
        ],
        "answer": "Access-Control-Allow-Origin"
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "question": "Which attack JWT prevents?",
        "options": [
            "CSRF",
            "XSS",
            "Replay",
            "Man in middle"
        ],
        "answer": "Replay"
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "question": "Which API principle uses nouns in URL?",
        "options": [
            "SOAP",
            "REST",
            "GraphQL",
            "RPC"
        ],
        "answer": "REST"
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "question": "Which method partially updates data?",
        "options": [
            "PUT",
            "PATCH",
            "POST",
            "UPDATE"
        ],
        "answer": "PATCH"
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "question": "Which API tool documents endpoints?",
        "options": [
            "Swagger",
            "Git",
            "Postman",
            "NPM"
        ],
        "answer": "Swagger"
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "question": "Which API uses schema-based queries?",
        "options": [
            "REST",
            "SOAP",
            "GraphQL",
            "RPC"
        ],
        "answer": "GraphQL"
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "question": "Which git command views commit history?",
        "options": [
            "git log",
            "git status",
            "git show",
            "git diff"
        ],
        "answer": "git log"
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "question": "Which git command stages files?",
        "options": [
            "git stage",
            "git add",
            "git commit",
            "git save"
        ],
        "answer": "git add"
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "question": "Which git file ignores files?",
        "options": [
            ".gitignore",
            ".ignore",
            ".gitconfig",
            ".npmignore"
        ],
        "answer": ".gitignore"
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "question": "Which tool checks API response?",
        "options": [
            "Browser",
            "Postman",
            "GitHub",
            "VS Code"
        ],
        "answer": "Postman"
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "question": "CI/CD automates?",
        "options": [
            "Testing",
            "Deployment",
            "Build",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "question": "Which layer handles business logic?",
        "options": [
            "View",
            "Controller",
            "Model",
            "Route"
        ],
        "answer": "Controller"
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "question": "Which caching improves performance?",
        "options": [
            "Browser cache",
            "DB cache",
            "Server cache",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "question": "Which design improves scalability?",
        "options": [
            "Monolith",
            "Microservices",
            "Single tier",
            "Tight coupling"
        ],
        "answer": "Microservices"
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "question": "Which skill is essential for fullstack?",
        "options": [
            "Only frontend",
            "Only backend",
            "Only database",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "question": "Full stack developer responsibility includes?",
        "options": [
            "UI",
            "API",
            "Database",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "question": "Which CSS unit is relative to parent?",
        "options": [
            "px",
            "em",
            "rem",
            "vh"
        ],
        "answer": "em"
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "question": "Which CSS property controls stacking order?",
        "options": [
            "position",
            "z-index",
            "display",
            "float"
        ],
        "answer": "z-index"
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "question": "Which CSS layout is best for 2D layouts?",
        "options": [
            "Flexbox",
            "Grid",
            "Float",
            "Inline"
        ],
        "answer": "Grid"
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "question": "JavaScript is ____ typed language?",
        "options": [
            "Strongly",
            "Statically",
            "Dynamically",
            "Strictly"
        ],
        "answer": "Dynamically"
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "question": "Which method clones array?",
        "options": [
            "slice()",
            "splice()",
            "copy()",
            "clone()"
        ],
        "answer": "slice()"
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "question": "Spread operator symbol is?",
        "options": [
            "...",
            "**",
            "=>",
            "::"
        ],
        "answer": "..."
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "question": "Arrow functions differ by?",
        "options": [
            "this binding",
            "syntax only",
            "speed",
            "scope"
        ],
        "answer": "this binding"
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "question": "Event bubbling moves?",
        "options": [
            "Child to parent",
            "Parent to child",
            "Random",
            "Parallel"
        ],
        "answer": "Child to parent"
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "question": "React StrictMode helps in?",
        "options": [
            "Production",
            "Debugging",
            "Styling",
            "Routing"
        ],
        "answer": "Debugging"
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "question": "Which hook prevents re-render?",
        "options": [
            "useState",
            "useRef",
            "useEffect",
            "useReducer"
        ],
        "answer": "useRef"
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "question": "Which React feature splits code?",
        "options": [
            "Memo",
            "Lazy",
            "Fragment",
            "Context"
        ],
        "answer": "Lazy"
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "question": "React Router handles?",
        "options": [
            "Auth",
            "Routing",
            "State",
            "UI"
        ],
        "answer": "Routing"
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "question": "SPA routing uses?",
        "options": [
            "Server routes",
            "Client routes",
            "DB routes",
            "API routes"
        ],
        "answer": "Client routes"
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "question": "Which Express middleware enables CORS?",
        "options": [
            "cors()",
            "allow()",
            "secure()",
            "origin()"
        ],
        "answer": "cors()"
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "question": "Which Node feature handles async?",
        "options": [
            "Threads",
            "Event Loop",
            "Processes",
            "Workers"
        ],
        "answer": "Event Loop"
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "question": "Which HTTP module creates server?",
        "options": [
            "net",
            "http",
            "server",
            "express"
        ],
        "answer": "http"
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "question": "Which Express method handles params?",
        "options": [
            "req.params",
            "req.query",
            "req.body",
            "req.path"
        ],
        "answer": "req.params"
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "question": "Which status code means Accepted?",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "201",
            "202",
            "204"
        ],
        "answer": "202"
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "question": "Laravel service container is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Routing",
            "Dependency injection",
            "Auth",
            "DB"
        ],
        "answer": "Dependency injection"
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "question": "Which Laravel feature listens events?",
        "options": [
            "Listeners",
            "Jobs",
            "Tasks",
            "Queues"
        ],
        "answer": "Listeners"
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "question": "Which artisan command clears cache?",
        "options": [
            "cache:clear",
            "config:clear",
            "route:clear",
            "view:clear"
        ],
        "answer": "cache:clear"
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "question": "Which Blade directive extends layout?",
        "options": [
            "@include",
            "@yield",
            "@extends",
            "@section"
        ],
        "answer": "@extends"
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "question": "Which Laravel feature handles files?",
        "options": [
            "Storage",
            "Upload",
            "Media",
            "Files"
        ],
        "answer": "Storage"
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "question": "Which join returns all left rows?",
        "options": [
            "INNER",
            "LEFT",
            "RIGHT",
            "CROSS"
        ],
        "answer": "LEFT"
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "question": "MongoDB aggregation is used for?",
        "options": [
            "Filtering",
            "Processing data",
            "Indexing",
            "Backup"
        ],
        "answer": "Processing data"
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "question": "Which index improves text search?",
        "options": [
            "Normal",
            "Unique",
            "Text",
            "Hash"
        ],
        "answer": "Text"
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "question": "ACID relates to?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Transactions",
            "Indexes",
            "Caching"
        ],
        "answer": "Transactions"
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "question": "Which auth uses OAuth?",
        "options": [
            "JWT",
            "Social login",
            "Session",
            "Basic"
        ],
        "answer": "Social login"
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "question": "CSRF attack targets?",
        "options": [
            "JWT",
            "Cookies",
            "Headers",
            "Tokens"
        ],
        "answer": "Cookies"
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "question": "XSS relates to?",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Frontend",
            "Auth",
            "API"
        ],
        "answer": "Frontend"
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "question": "HTTPS provides?",
        "options": [
            "Speed",
            "Encryption",
            "Caching",
            "Routing"
        ],
        "answer": "Encryption"
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "question": "REST best practice uses nouns for?",
        "options": [
            "Actions",
            "Resources",
            "Methods",
            "Headers"
        ],
        "answer": "Resources"
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "question": "HATEOAS is part of?",
        "options": [
            "REST",
            "SOAP",
            "GraphQL",
            "RPC"
        ],
        "answer": "REST"
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "question": "API versioning is done via?",
        "options": [
            "URL",
            "Header",
            "Query",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "question": "Caching API responses improves?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Performance",
            "Auth",
            "DB size"
        ],
        "answer": "Performance"
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "question": "Stateless APIs scale better because?",
        "options": [
            "No session",
            "Fast DB",
            "More memory",
            "Cookies"
        ],
        "answer": "No session"
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "question": "Which git command reverts commit?",
        "options": [
            "git reset",
            "git revert",
            "git undo",
            "git back"
        ],
        "answer": "git revert"
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "question": "Rebase is used to?",
        "options": [
            "Delete commits",
            "Rewrite history",
            "Merge safely",
            "Deploy"
        ],
        "answer": "Rewrite history"
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "question": "CI/CD stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Code Integration",
            "Continuous Integration / Delivery",
            "Compile Install",
            "Control Deploy"
        ],
        "answer": "Continuous Integration / Delivery"
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "question": "Postman collections are used to?",
        "options": [
            "Group APIs",
            "Deploy APIs",
            "Secure APIs",
            "Build APIs"
        ],
        "answer": "Group APIs"
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "question": "Environment variables avoid?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Hardcoding secrets",
            "Errors",
            "Routing"
        ],
        "answer": "Hardcoding secrets"
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "question": "Scalable apps require?",
        "options": [
            "Tight coupling",
            "Loose coupling",
            "Hardcoding",
            "Global state"
        ],
        "answer": "Loose coupling"
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "question": "DRY principle means?",
        "options": [
            "Do Repeat Yourself",
            "Don't Repeat Yourself",
            "Debug Regularly Yourself",
            "Deploy Rapidly Yourself"
        ],
        "answer": "Don't Repeat Yourself"
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "question": "SOLID principles improve?",
        "options": [
            "UI",
            "Maintainability",
            "Speed",
            "Auth"
        ],
        "answer": "Maintainability"
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "question": "Logging helps in?",
        "options": [
            "Styling",
            "Debugging",
            "Routing",
            "Caching"
        ],
        "answer": "Debugging"
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "question": "Production-ready app should have?",
        "options": [
            "Console logs",
            "Error handling",
            "Hardcoded keys",
            "No validation"
        ],
        "answer": "Error handling"
    }
]